Guide to the Organization for Tropical Studies Records, 1962 - 1974 UA.26.03.0029
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Organization for Tropical Studies records
1962 - 1974
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Organization for Tropical Studies
UA.26.03.0029
10.5 Linear Feet
The Organization for Tropical Studies (OTS), founded in 1963, has had its North American Office located at Duke University since 1976. The OTS offers students, faculty, and researchers opportunities to work hands-on in tropical sciences in Costa Rica and other Latin American countries. The Organization for Tropical Studies Records contain correspondence, administrative materials, reports, memoranda, and course materials from the early years of OTS. The focus of the collection is on the administrative structure of OTS and planning the course offerings in Latin America. Major correspondents include Jorge Campabadal, J. T. Spencer, and Kenneth J. Turnbull. Major topics include tropical biology, geography, meteorology, earth science, and forestry, and the National Science Foundation. English.
10,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Organization for Tropical Studies Records was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1979.
Historical Note
Several international conferences held in 1962 and 1963 brought together representatives from a number of universities to discuss the possibility of an international program in tropical biology to foster education and research. The Organization for Tropical Studies (OTS) formally began in 1963 as an educational program that offered graduate students and faculty hands-on experience in tropical biology. In February 1963, the OTS was officially incorporated as a non-profit organization, and the first Board meeting was held in Miami, Florida in June 1963. The ten charter members of OTS were: Harvard University, the Universities of Southern California, California (System), Washington, Kansas, Michigan, Miami, Florida, Costa Rica, and Louisiana State University. The OTS now has 63 members from across the Americas.
OTS offers a number of courses in biology, geography, meteorology, earth science, forestry, and other tropical sciences. The courses generally last two to three months, and draw students from the United States, Latin America, and elsewhere. At its three biological stations in Costa Rica and other Latin American locations, over 3,600 graduate students have participated in OTS programs since 1963. OTS employs a full-time administrative staff, but all OTS faculty are temporary, drawn from member institutions to teach their specialties, providing a dynamic experience for students. In addition, scientists come to the Costa Rican stations to conduct research throughout the year.
OTS had its North American Office (NAO) in Miami, Florida from its founding to 1976, when the NAO moved to Duke University in Durham, North Carolina. Donald Stone, now professor emeritus in biology, served as Executive Director. The OTS also maintains a Costa Rican Office. The OTS website, which offers additional information, is located at: http://www.ots.duke.edu.
Collection Overview
The Organization for Tropical Studies Records includes correspondence, administrative materials, reports, memoranda, and course materials from the early years of OTS. The focus of the collection is on the administrative structure of OTS and planning the course offerings in Latin America. Major correspondents include Jorge Campabadal, J. T. Spencer, and Kenneth J. Turnbull. Major topics include tropical biology, geography, meteorology, earth science, and forestry, and the National Science Foundation. The collection is organized into two series. The Administrative series contains correspondence from the North American Office, as well as correspondence with OTS administrators and faculty. In addition, the series has information on committees, sources of funding, founding documents, and topics related to the administration of OTS. The second series, Courses, has information on the planning, curriculum, course participants, critiques, and other aspects of educational programming offered by OTS.
Related Material
Organization for Tropical Studies Reference Collection
University Archives, Duke University
Organization for Tropical Studies Records, 1948-1986
University Archives and Records Program, University of Michigan
Biology -- Tropics; Earth sciences -- Tropics; Education -- Tropics; Forests and forestry -- Tropics; Geography -- Tropics; Research -- Costa Rica; Research -- Tropics; Tropical meteorology; Campabadal, Jorge R.; National Science Foundation (U.S.); Spencer, Jack Taif, 1912-; Turnbull, Kenneth James, 1927-; Organization for Tropical Studies; Organization for Tropical Studies
- Administrative, 1962-1974
  Scope and Contents note
  The Administrative series begins with correspondence. The Reading File is a collection of all the outgoing correspondence of the North American Office. Most of this correspondence is written by J. T. Spencer and Kenneth J. Turnbull, Executive Directors of OTS. Following the Reading Files is correspondence organized by the name of the sender. Much of this correspondence is from Jorge Campabadal of the Costa Rican Office. All of the correspondence is arranged in chronological order, with the latest materials in the front of the folders.
  In addition to correspondence, the Administrative series contains committee materials, founding materials, information on funding (much of which came from the National Science Foundation), and other topics of importance to OTS. These materials are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Reading File
      - October 1966-December 1967, A-D (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - October 1966-December 1967, E-I (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - October 1966-December 1967, J-N (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - October 1966-December 1967, O-S (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - October 1966-December 1967, T-Z (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - January 1968-December 1968, A-B (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - January 1968-December 1968, C (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - January 1968-December 1968, D-F (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - January 1968-December 1968, G-H (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - January 1968-December 1968, I-L (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - January 1968-December 1968, M (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - January 1968-December 1968, N-R (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - January 1968-December 1968, S-T (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - January 1968-December 1968, U-Z (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - January 1, 1969-January 15, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - January 16, 1969-January 23, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - January 24, 1969-February 10, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - February 11, 1969-February 20, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - February 21, 1969-March 10, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - March 11, 1969-March 28, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - April 1, 1969-April 30, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - May 1, 1969-May 31, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - June 1, 1969-June 30, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - July 1, 1969-July 31, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - August 1, 1969-August 31, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - September 1, 1969-September 20, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - September 21, 1969-September 30, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - October 1, 1969-October 23, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - October 24, 1969-October 31, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - November 1, 1969-November 30, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - December 1, 1969-December 15, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - December 16, 1969-December 31, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - January 1, 1970-January 31, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - February 1, 1970-February 11, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - February 12, 1970-February 28, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - March 1, 1970-March 12, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - March 13, 1970-March 31, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - April 1, 1970-April 30, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - May 1, 1970-May 15, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - May 16, 1970-May 31, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - June 1, 1970-June 15, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - June 16, 1970-June 30, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - July 1, 1970-July 15, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - July 16, 1970-July 31, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - August 1, 1970-August 15, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - August 16, 1970-August 31, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - September 1, 1970-September 30, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - October 1, 1970-October 15, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - October 16, 1970-October 31, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - November 1, 1970-November 30, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - December 1, 1970-December 31, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - January 1, 1971-January 15, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - January 16, 1971-January 31, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - February 1, 1971-February 28, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - March 1, 1971-March 15, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - March 16, 1971-March 31, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - April 1, 1971-April 30, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - May 1, 1971-May 31, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - June 1, 1971-June 30, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - July 1, 1971-July 15, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - July 16, 1971-July 31, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - August 1, 1971-August 15, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 62)
      - August 16, 1971-August 31 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      - September 1, 1971-September 30, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - October 1, 1971-October 15, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - October 16, 1971-October 31, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - November 1, 1971-November 30, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - December 1, 1971-December 31, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - January 1, 1972-January 31, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - February 1, 1972-February 15, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      - February 16, 1972-February 29, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - March 1, 1972-March 31, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - April 1, 1972-April 30, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 73)
      - May 1, 1972-May 31, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - June 1, 1972-June 30, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - July 1, 1972-October 31, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 76)
      - November 1, 1972-April 30, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 77)
      - May 1, 1973-September 30, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 78)
      - October 1, 1973-December 31, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 79)
      - January 1, 1974-February 28, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 80)
      - March 1, 1974-March 31, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 81)
      - April 1, 1974-May 31, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 82)
      - June 1, 1974-July 31, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 83)
      - August 1, 1974-December 5, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Costa Rican Office, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - North American Office, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - General
      - 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 87)
      - 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 88)
      - 1966-1972 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Roderico Anzueto, December 1969-January 1971 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - James S. Bethel, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Wayne Cain, January 1972 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Jorge Campabadal
      - January 1968-June 1968 (Box 3, Folder 93)
      - July 1968-December 1968 (Box 3, Folder 94)
      - January 1969-June 1969 (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - July 1969-October 1969 (Box 3, Folder 96)
      - November 1969-December 1969 (Box 3, Folder 97)
      - January 1970 (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - February 1970 (Box 3, Folder 99)
      - March 1970 (Box 3, Folder 100)
      - April 1970-June 1970 (Box 3, Folder 101)
      - July 1970-August 1970 (Box 3, Folder 102)
      - September 1970-February 1971 (Box 3, Folder 103)
      - March 1971-December 1971 (Box 3, Folder 104)
      - January 1972-December 1972 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - John De Abate, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Ronald S. Dewitt, September 1969-July 1970 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Robert Dorian, August 1967-December 1969 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Robert Dorian, January 1970-February 1972 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Norman Hartweg, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Grace B. Iverson, January 1972-February 1972 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Steven Preston, May 1965-May 1967 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Steven Preston, April 1967-January 1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Reed Rollins, May 1963-October 1965, undated (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - J. T. Spencer, January 1966-December 1972 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Larry Stuart, August 1969-January 1972 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Kenneth Turnbull, June 1972-December 1972 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Benjamin Waite, Residential Coodinator, December 1970-December 1972 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Committees
    - Agriculture Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Agriculture Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Anthropology Committee, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Anthropology Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Earth Sciences Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Earth Sciences Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Executive Committee
      - Agreement between the University of Miama and OTS, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 125)
      - November 1970 Annual Meeting (Box 4, Folder 126)
      - November 1971 Annual Meeting (Box 4, Folder 127)
      - Board Election, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 128)
      - Board Funds for Meetings, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 129)
      - October 1969 Board of Directors Election, August 1969-January 1970 (Box 4, Folder 130)
      - Budgets, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 131)
      - Charter and By-laws, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 132)
      - Confirmed Institutional Representatives, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 133)
      - Confirmed Institutional Representatives, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 134)
      - Consolidated Budgets, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 135)
      - Correspondence
        - 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 136)
        - April 1970-September 1970 (Box 4, Folder 137)
        - October 1970-January 1971 (Box 4, Folder 138)
        - February 1971-May 1971 (Box 4, Folder 139)
        - June 1971-November 1971 (Box 4, Folder 140)
        - On old fiscal records, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 141)
        - Secretary Marion Marts, June 1969-November 1972 (Box 4, Folder 142)
      - Ford Foundation Pilot Grant, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 143)
      - April 1971 Meeting, December 1970-April 1971 (Box 4, Folder 144)
      - Meeting References, April 1971 (Box 4, Folder 145-146)
      - Membership Committee Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 147)
      - Membership Lists, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 148)
      - Memoranda, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 149)
      - National Science Foundation (NSF)
        - Alice Withrow Correspondence, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 150)
        - Education Grant, 1963-1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 151)
        - Education Grant, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 152)
        - Expenditure Ceiling, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 153)
        - Grant GZ-687, Interim Report #1 Records, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 154)
        - Grant GB 7805 Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 155)
        - Grant GB 7805 Records, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 156)
        - Indirect Costs, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 157)
        - Meeting, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 158)
      - Rockefeller Proposal, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 159)
      - Teaching for OTS, October 1968 (Box 5, Folder 160)
      - Texas System of National Laboratories, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 161)
      - Tuition Question, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - Forestry Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Forestry Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Meteorology Committee
      - 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 165)
      - 1969 (Box 5, Folder 166)
      - 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Operating Committee, September 1969-December 1971 (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Research Committee, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Statewide Committee on Tropical Studies Minutes, January 1967 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - U of Hawaii Tropical Studies Committee, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Founding Material
    - Board of Directors and Advisor Council Material, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Board of Directors and Advisor Council Material, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Board of Directors and Advisor Council Minutes, 1963-1967 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Descriptive Material, 1964-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Formative Documents, 1962-1963, undated (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - Institutional Representatives, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - OTS Information, December 1965-March 1966 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Funding
    - Billing to Research Accounting, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - 1965-1970 Budget, circa 1964 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Form 10s, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Invoices, September 1965-December 1966 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Invoices to OTS Members, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF)
      - NSF-AID Program, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 184)
      - Grant, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 185)
      - Grant Application, December 11, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 186)
      - Grant Extension Application, circa 1967 (Box 5, Folder 187)
      - Grant, Final Report, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 188)
      - Grant Report, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 189)
      - Proposals from OTS, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 190)
      - New Member Fees, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 191)
      - Requisitions and Purchase Orders, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Topics
    - Associated Universities, Inc., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Costa Rica, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Costa Rica, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Education - General, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Field Stations, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 197)
    - Guatemala, June 1970-August 1971 (Box 6, Folder 198)
    - Inventory, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - Lecture Announcement, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - Membership, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 201)
    - New Members, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Nicoya Peninsula Report, May 1962 (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - OTS Report on its Program of Tropical Studies and Research, August 5, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - Program for a Cooperative Program in Education and Research, January 8, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Regulations, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 206)
    - Reports from San Jose, Costa Rica, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - Reports - Preston, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 208)
    - Research, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 209)
    - Research Project, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Tropical Science Center, Annual Report, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Tropical Science Center information, undated (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - USC Tropical Studies Program, December 1967 (Box 6, Folder 213)
- Courses, 1962-1974
  The Courses series contains information about the OTS's educational programs. Most of the materials are related to individual classes in the tropical sciences. These are arranged chronologically by course session date. Some courses have numbers (i.e. #71-4); when available, these have been provided. Also included in this series are course critiques, planning information, and other materials related to OTS courses.
  - Tropical Forest Ecology, 1965 (February-March 1965 session) (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - Biology and Evolution of Tropical Insects, 1965 (July-August 1965 session) (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Fundamentals Course, 1965 (July-August 1965 session) (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - The Biology of Tropical Epiphytes, 1966 (February-March 1966 session) (Box 6, Folder 217)
  - The Biology of Tropical Vertebrates, 1966 (February-March 1966 session) (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - Fundamentals Course, 1966 (February-March 1966 session) (Box 6, Folder 219)
  - The Biology of Tropical Grasses, 1966 (July-August 1966 session) (Box 6, Folder 220)
  - Fundamentals Course, 1966 (July-August 1966 session) (Box 6, Folder 221)
  - Tropical Biology Course, 1966-1967 (February-March 1967 session) (Box 6, Folder 222)
  - Insect Ecology in the Tropics, 1967 (February-March 1967 session) (Box 6, Folder 223)
  - The Biology of Tropical Pteridophytes, 1965-1967 (Summer 1967 session) (Box 6, Folder 224)
  - Tropical Biology - An Ecological Approach, 1967 (July-August 1967 session) (Box 6, Folder 225-226)
  - Tropical Lands and their Utilization, 1965-1967 (July-August 1967 session) (Box 6, Folder 227)
  - Crop Plants in Tropical Environments, 1967-1968 (February-March 1968 session) (Box 6, Folder 228)
  - Problems in Tropical Forestry, 1967-1968 (February-March 1968 session) (Box 6, Folder 229)
  - Tropical Biology: An Ecological Approach, 1967-1968 (February-March 1968 session) (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - Land and Life in the Tropics, 1968 (July-August 1968 session) (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Reproductive Biology in Tropical Plant Ecology, 1968 (July-August 1968 session) (Box 6, Folder 232)
  - Tropical Biology: An Ecological Approach, 1967-1968 (July-August 1968 session) (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - Field Dendrology, 1968 (August-September 1968 session) (Box 6, Folder 234)
  - Tropical Biology - An Ecological Approach, 1968 (July-August 1968 session) (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - Field Dendrology, 1968 (August-September 1968 session) (Box 6, Folder 236)
  - Principles of Tropical Grassland Agriculture, 1968-1969 (February-March 1969 session) (Box 6, Folder 237)
  - Tropical Biology, 1968-1969 (February-March 1969 session) (Box 6, Folder 238)
  - Introduction to Tropical Forestry, 1968-1969 (April-June 1969 session) (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - Advanced Population Biology, 1968-1969 (July-August 1969 session) (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - Tropical Biology: An Ecological Approach, 1968-1969 (July-August 1969 session) (Box 6, Folder 241)
  - Tropical Biometerorology, 1968 (July-August 1969 session) (Box 6, Folder 242)
  - Tropical Marine Biology, 1966-1969 (July-August 1969 session) (Box 6, Folder 243)
  - #70-1: Tropical Biology - An Ecological Approach, 1969-1970 (February-March 1970 session) (Box 6, Folder 244)
  - #70-2: Tropical Limnology, 1969-1971 (February-March 1970 session) (Box 6, Folder 245)
  - #70-3: Animal Science, 1969-1971 (February-March 1970 session--cancelled) (Box 6, Folder 246)
  - #70-4: Geology, 1969-1970 (February-March 1970 session) (Box 6, Folder 247)
  - #70-5: Geography of Costa Rica, 1969-1971 (April-June 1970 session) (Box 7, Folder 248)
  - #70-6: Tropical Forestry, 1970 (April-June 1970 session) (Box 7, Folder 249)
  - #70-7: Tropical Biology, Section 1, 1969-1971 (July-August 1970 session) (Box 7, Folder 250)
  - #70-8: Tropical Biology (Faculty), 1970 (July-August 1970 session) (Box 7, Folder 251)
  - #70-9: Atmospheric Sciences, 1969-1970 (July-August 1970 session) (Box 7, Folder 252)
  - #70-10: Tropical Marine Biology, 1969-1971 (July-August 1970 session) (Box 7, Folder 253)
  - #71-1: Tropical Biology, 1970-1971 (February-March 1971 session) (Box 7, Folder 254-255)
  - #71-2: Vertebrates, 1970-1971 (April-May 1971 session) (Box 7, Folder 256)
  - #71-3: Tropical Forestry, 1970-1972 (April-June 1971 session) (Box 7, Folder 257-258)
  - #71-4: Geology, 1970-1971 (June-August 1971 session) (Box 7, Folder 259)
  - #71-5 and 71-6: Tropical Biology, 1970-1971 (July-August 1971 session) (Box 7, Folder 260)
  - #71-7: Geography, 1970-1972 (July-August 1971 session) (Box 7, Folder 261-262)
  - #71-8: Atmospheric Energy Considerations, 1970-1972 (July-August 1971 session) (Box 7, Folder 263)
  - #72-1: Tropical Biology, 1972 (January-March 1972 session) (Box 7, Folder 264)
  - #72-2: Advanced Biology: Central American Pine Forests, 1971-1972 (April-May 1972 session) (Box 7, Folder 265)
  - #72-3: Tropical Biology, 1972 (July-August 1972 session) (Box 7, Folder 266)